<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Richwood&#039;s Past Archives - Dustin K. Lowe</title>
	<atom:link href="/category/richwoods-past/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/category/richwoods-past/</link>
	<description>Books by Author Dustin K. Lowe</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 19:15:14 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/cropped-DL-logo-bg-x144.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>Richwood&#039;s Past Archives - Dustin K. Lowe</title>
	<link>/category/richwoods-past/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">160639128</site>	<item>
		<title>Joseph Embrey, Richwood Jeweler</title>
		<link>/joseph-embrey/</link>
					<comments>/joseph-embrey/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dustin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 11 Aug 2023 19:15:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richwood's Past]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[embrey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[jeweler]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=4042</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For 51 years, Joseph Embrey had been engaged in the jewelry business in Richwood, Ohio. His father was a jeweler, and all of the sons followed the same trade. Mr. Embrey had been located in the same building in Richwood for the past twenty-six years. He had the honor of conducting one of the oldest...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>For 51 years, Joseph Embrey had been engaged in the jewelry business in Richwood, Ohio. His father was a jeweler, and all of the sons followed the same trade. Mr. Embrey had been located in the same building in Richwood for the past twenty-six years. He had the honor of conducting one of the oldest continuous businesses in Richwood.</p>



<p>Joseph Embrey was the son of Lewis and Margaret (Bell) Embrey and was born in East Liberty, Ohio on July 1, 1855. His father was a native of Virginia, and his mother was born in Scotland. Lewis Embrey was a watchmaker and jeweler at East Liberty and lived there until his death in 1887 at the age of seventy-nine. His wife died in 1904 at the age of eighty-three. Lewis was a member of the famous &#8220;Squirrel Hunters&#8221; brigade in the Civil War. They had six children: George, Maggie, John, Victoria, Joseph, and Robert.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1908-Eagle-Drug.jpg?resize=252%2C384&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4043" style="width:252px;height:384px" width="252" height="384" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1908-Eagle-Drug.jpg?w=523&amp;ssl=1 523w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1908-Eagle-Drug.jpg?resize=197%2C300&amp;ssl=1 197w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1908-Eagle-Drug.jpg?resize=263%2C400&amp;ssl=1 263w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1908-Eagle-Drug.jpg?resize=460%2C700&amp;ssl=1 460w" sizes="(max-width: 252px) 100vw, 252px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>Original location of Embrey Jewelry Store from 1878 until 1888.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Before beginning to learn the watchmaker&#8217;s trade at the age of sixteen, Joseph spent three years working in a woolen mill. He learned the watchmaker&#8217;s and jeweler&#8217;s trade with his brother George in Morrow, Ohio. Joseph arrived in Richwood on May 29, 1878, and established a watchmaking and jewelry business at the northwest corner of Franklin and Ottawa Street (what is now Subway). He later moved to the east side of Franklin Street in 1888 where he stayed until he retired in 1931.</p>



<p>Joseph married Clara Bowers on November 11, 1883 and had two sons, Morrow and Edward. Morrow was a mechanical engineer in Milwaukee and a superintendent of a power plant there. Edward, the youngest son, was a watchmaker and helped run his father&#8217;s store for a time until his untimely death in 1930 at the age of 41. Mr. and Mrs. Embrey were members of the Methodist Episcopal church. Joseph was a church trustee and treasurer for fifteen years. He was also a member of Mount Carmel Lodge No. 303, Free and Accepted Masons, and a member of the Knights of Pythias, Rising Sun Lodge No. 71.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1910-Embry-House.jpg?resize=461%2C303&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-4044" style="width:461px;height:303px" width="461" height="303" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1910-Embry-House.jpg?w=792&amp;ssl=1 792w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1910-Embry-House.jpg?resize=300%2C197&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1910-Embry-House.jpg?resize=768%2C505&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1910-Embry-House.jpg?resize=700%2C460&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/08/1910-Embry-House.jpg?resize=400%2C263&amp;ssl=1 400w" sizes="(max-width: 461px) 100vw, 461px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>The Embrey House, located on East Ottawa St. and erected in 1895 by Joseph Embrey. Photo taken circa 1910.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Joseph and Clara Embrey lived on East Ottawa Street, where Joseph had constructed their home in 1895. Joseph retired from his jewelry store in 1931 due to declining health. Joseph&#8217;s granddaughter, Jean, born to Morrow Embrey, was a graduate nurse and had cared for her grandfather during his illness. After a six-month battle with complications, he passed away on October 5, 1934, at the age of 79. Rev. H.M. Carpenter, a pastor of the Richwood M.E. church, conducted the funeral services at the Embrey home. Interment, under the charge of Lloyd Winter &amp; Son, was made in Claibourne cemetery. Clara Embrey later passed away on September 14, 1941, at the age of 81.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/joseph-embrey/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">4042</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Old Richwood Cemetery</title>
		<link>/old-richwood-cemetery/</link>
					<comments>/old-richwood-cemetery/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dustin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 10 Feb 2023 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richwood's Past]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[graveyard]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[old richwood cemetery]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3965</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the church in front of the cemetery is now for sale, I thought it would be prudent to offer a history of the lot. The first person to be buried in the cemetery was Jane Mary Brookins, daughter of J.P. Brookins. The story goes as follows: &#8220;Jane Mary, the little daughter and only child...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since the church in front of the cemetery is now for sale, I thought it would be prudent to offer a history of the lot. The first person to be buried in the cemetery was Jane Mary Brookins, daughter of J.P. Brookins. The story goes as follows:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Jane Mary, the little daughter and only child of Dr. and Mrs. Brookins, was playing with her cousins, William and John Woods, and each had a fire. Jane Mary&#8217;s was burning well, but the boys could not get theirs to burn and asked to make them burn. She took her apron to fan the fire and sat down over some hot coals that had scattered, and her clothing took fire from them. Before help could reach her, she was so badly burned that she died in a few hours.&#8221;</p>
<cite>A Voice From the Past by W.H. Frank</cite></blockquote>



<p>Philip Plummer, the founder of Richwood, owned the plat and allowed the child to be buried there. He helped clear off the ground and dig the grave for said child. The graveyard grew throughout the years just as Richwood had grown. The cemetery had ceased to be used by around 1860. Some remains were even transferred to the Claibourne cemetery which is now the widely used cemetery in the area. In fact, the Richwood Gazette reported in 1877 how the old lot was full of weeds high enough to hide the tombstones; they implored the Trustees of the township to pay more attention to the place. The burial ground even became a hangout spot for young adults in the town who refused to stay out of trouble. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone.jpeg?resize=353%2C471&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3979" width="353" height="471" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone-rotated.jpeg?resize=768%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone-rotated.jpeg?resize=225%2C300&amp;ssl=1 225w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone-rotated.jpeg?resize=1152%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1152w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone-rotated.jpeg?resize=1536%2C2048&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone-rotated.jpeg?resize=700%2C933&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone-rotated.jpeg?resize=300%2C400&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone-rotated.jpeg?resize=525%2C700&amp;ssl=1 525w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Jane-Mary-Brookins-Tombstone-rotated.jpeg?resize=975%2C1300&amp;ssl=1 975w" sizes="(max-width: 353px) 100vw, 353px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>The tombstone of Jane Mary Brookins still located in the cemetery.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The First Baptist Church of Richwood received permission by the Trustees of Claibourne township to lease the lot and build their church in front of the cemetery on Ottawa street for a term of 99 years. The congregation would pay one dollar to the treasury of Claibourne Township with the stipulation that the church keep both the building and the graveyard in good repair and to have a fence constructed to enclose the lots. If at anytime the church building shall cease to be used as a house of worship by said Baptist society, then the lot shall become the property of Claibourne township once again.</p>



<p>In 1889, 57 years after Richwood was founded, the heirs of Philip Plummer claimed that since the ground was no longer used for cemetery purposes, it should revert back to the original owner, Philip Plummer. They had brought a suit against the Baptist Church to compel them to pay for the land. The amount they claimed was $200.</p>



<p>On Monday, December 9, 1889, the trial began in the Marysville Courthouse at one o&#8217;clock p.m. John Graham was the first witness. He came to Richwood in 1886. He knew Philip Plummer well, and told the court of his good ways but wasn&#8217;t as specific with times and places and others were. Elder Swartz was the next witness and was well acquainted with the ground on which Richwood now stands. He was present at the time, in 1832, that Plummer drove into what is now the original town plat and saw them unload the surveyor&#8217;s tools that were used in laying off the town. In 1838, he (Swartz) heard Plummer say that he would not disturb the graves that had been made on the lots called the graveyard in Richwood; that he had given them to the people, and they had buried on them by his permission and should not be disturbed. He also told of the first grave that had been dug there, Jane Mary Brookins, and that he had burned his hands in trying to help extinguish the fire.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=447%2C335&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3970" width="447" height="335" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=1024%2C768&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=300%2C225&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=768%2C576&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=1536%2C1152&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=2048%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=700%2C525&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=400%2C300&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?resize=1300%2C975&amp;ssl=1 1300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/IMG_3378.jpeg?w=4000&amp;ssl=1 4000w" sizes="(max-width: 447px) 100vw, 447px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>View of half of the cemetery. The tombstone leaning against the tree is the one that belongs to Jane Mary Brookins. Her exact burial place is unknown, the tombstone being moved from it&#8217;s original position.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>John A.J. Tonguet next took the stand. His age was 83. He also met Plummer in the woods when he came to lay out the town. His uncle, George Clark, took a contract from Plummer to clear and fence the three acres of land immediately east of Richwood and lying between the Prospect and the Hoskins pikes. Uncle George Clark and Nathaniel and John A.J. Tonguet did the work; and when they were ready to commence to make the fence, Plummer came to help lay out the fence row, and the question was asked if the fence should be on the survey line or not. Plummer responded with, &#8220;No; I own the land in both surveys, and I want the fence put on the line of the graveyard and other lots, and let the driveway, or the strip of land between the corporation line on the east and west line of the Bull of Claibourne survey be inside the field and the graveyard lots outside.&#8221; They then set the stakes for the fence by the stakes of the lots of the town. This was in 1835.</p>



<p>William H. Ferguson came next. He produced a deed from Plummer for two unrelated lots that were turned back to Plummer in 1849 by act of the Legislature, and the facts were set up in the deed.</p>



<p>L. Myers came to Richwood in the spring of 1842, and buried his children in the lots.</p>



<p>John Phillips was born in Richwood in 1836 and remembered Plummer and the graveyard lots well.</p>



<p>Asa Langstaff was a Trustee of Claibourne Township and as such made the lease of the lots to the church. This testimony was most all taken in writing on Monday. The stipulations of which is explained above.</p>



<p>Tuesday morning, the court came and H.C. Hamilton was put on the stand. For an hour or more, he told the story of Richwood and the old settlers to an audience of forty or more, mostly lawyers, who gave the best of attention, and now and then indulged in a smile as some peculiar part came to light. He knew Plummer and all his family. He went to school with the older children and knew the younger ones as well. Plummer left Richwood in 1842, early in the fall. He returned on a visit in 1843, during the Millerite movement and the Second Great Awakening that never came. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Old-Richwood-Cemetery-Map.png?resize=591%2C401&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3968" width="591" height="401" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Old-Richwood-Cemetery-Map.png?resize=1024%2C695&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Old-Richwood-Cemetery-Map.png?resize=300%2C203&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Old-Richwood-Cemetery-Map.png?resize=768%2C521&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Old-Richwood-Cemetery-Map.png?resize=700%2C475&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Old-Richwood-Cemetery-Map.png?resize=400%2C271&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Old-Richwood-Cemetery-Map.png?resize=1300%2C882&amp;ssl=1 1300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2023/01/Old-Richwood-Cemetery-Map.png?w=1467&amp;ssl=1 1467w" sizes="(max-width: 591px) 100vw, 591px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption"><em>A map of the Richwood Cemetery lot.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Plummer came back to Richwood as a minister of the Methodist Episcopal church in the fall of 1849 and stayed for two years. The people used the Richwood burying ground when H.C. Hamilton left home, in 1853, and they had to a great extent abandoned the use of it when he returned in 1859. The late Joshua S. Gill got the field east of town and the lots west of the graveyard and fenced them all as one piece of land and used the graveyard lots as a pasture field to connect the field and his house and lots.</p>



<p>In the spring of 1864, the late William Hamilton bought Gill out. Hamilton did not own the lots and lands long before he sold them to Edward Norris. Norris abandoned the field and laid it off in town lots. From this on the graveyard was neglected, and it became an immense weed patch up until in was leased to the Baptist church. Under control of the church, the graveyard for a time became a pleasant place to go and look upon. The case was decided that the church would still hold possession of the lots. It had continued to stay in possession of the people of Richwood just as Philip Plummer wanted.</p>



<p>Since then the church had changed congregations a few times until now. The building has been largely renovated and is now for sale. The graveyard, however, continues to be neglected just as it was over 160 years ago.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/old-richwood-cemetery/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3965</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Varuna Park: The God of Waters</title>
		<link>/varuna-park/</link>
					<comments>/varuna-park/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dustin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2022 18:03:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richwood's Past]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[mineral water]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[varuan water company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[varuna]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[varuna park]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://rnulibraryblog.wordpress.com/?p=3411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While Magnetic Springs was famous for it’s healing mineral water, Richwood was no stranger to these discoveries. Mineral water was thought to provide many benefits. By the 19th century, thermal resorts had become fashionable destinations for those who wished to bathe and enjoy the therapeutic benefits of mineral water. Many hoped to find miracle cures...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>While Magnetic Springs was famous for it’s healing mineral water, Richwood was no stranger to these discoveries. Mineral water was thought to provide many benefits. By the 19th century, thermal resorts had become fashionable destinations for those who wished to bathe and enjoy the therapeutic benefits of mineral water. Many hoped to find miracle cures for their ailments.</p>



<p>The C.D. Sidle farm in Richwood was located slightly west of the fairgrounds. In 1899, the Richwood Oil, Gas, and Mineral Company, of which a man named J.L. Horn was president, awarded a contract to an experienced driller from Lima, Ohio for the drilling of two test oil wells on the land of Mr. Sidle. Under the terms of the agreement, the contract price for the drilling of the first well was 95 cents per foot until the hole was 100 feet provided oil or gas was not found. If none was discovered, the drilling would continue until the company wishes to stop and the contractor would be paid $1.25 for each foot drilled. While oil or gas was never found, something else entirely was discovered. </p>



<p>On September 19, 1899, the oil well reached a depth of 1652 feet when a vein of mineral water was struck. Dr. L.L. Roebuck was sent to Columbus with a sample of the water to have it analyzed. He went directly to Curtis C. Howard who was a professor of chemistry at the Starling Medical College. Howard said the water was strongly charged with minerals and began analyzing it straight away. Although quite a number of people were disappointed that no oil was found, the board of directors admitted that if it is indeed mineral water, it would be worth more money than an oil or gas well. A few days after the drilling, the water raised in the well to a depth of 1200 feet and it may have eventually overflowed. </p>



<p>At the oil drilling meeting held at the mayor’s office on the 26th of September, 1899, a large list of shareholders were present and it was decided to drill another well. The shareholders were required to pay in the last half of their assessment no later than Oct. 7 of that year. As soon as sufficient funds were raised, a contract would be made for the drilling of the second well. The analysis of the water had not yet been received by Prof. Howard at the time. However, in a letter that the professor wrote to Dr. Roebuck a few days prior, he mentioned that the water contained valuable medicinal properties and requested that the doctor wait until a thorough chemical test could be made.</p>



<p>A few days later, the results had finally arrived of a thorough quantitative analysis of the water from Richwood’s abandoned oil well. He submitted the result of his investigations to the directors of the Richwood Oil, Gas, and Mineral Company in the following letter:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">GENTLEMEN : - The sample of deep well water received from you gives on analysis the following figures:
Sodium Sulphate.................................................145.2
Sodium Chloride................................................1465.1
Calcium Chloride.................................................80.6
Calcium Bicarbonate..............................................77.3
Magnesium Bicarbonate............................................80.9
Aluminum Sulphate................................................21.6
                                                               ______
                                                               1870.7
Sulphuretted Hydrogen..............................24.3 cubic inches.
                       Yours Truly,
                               Curtis C. Howard</pre>



<p>In transmitting his report, Professor Howard said: &#8220;The water contains a considerable amount of sodium chloride present. The calcium chloride is also considerable and the aluminum sulphate is unusually high. The water certainly possesses a sufficiently large amount of mineral constituents to entitle it to be called mineral water.&#8221; Professor Howard’s area of expertise was of course to simply determine the chemical composition of the water and it was not a part of his duty to express an opinion as to its medical value. The proportion of sulphuretted hydrogen in this water, as compared with other sulpher waters, is shown in the following table:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">Sulphuretted hydrogen gas in cubic inches per U.S. gal.
Weilbach Well, Germany............................................1.161
Cave Well, Chittenago, N.Y........................................2.754
White Sulphur Well, Chittenago, N.Y...............................0.884
Florida Well, Montgomery Co., N.Y.................................3.765
Odevene Spring, Delaware, Ohio....................................2.924
Richwood Well, Richwood, Ohio......................................24.3</pre>



<p>The Odevene spring of Delaware is still located on Ohio Wesleyan University&#8217;s campus. The sulphur spring well, which has since dried up, has been turned into a well-known gathering spot for students and faculty. The well only contained 2.9 cubic inches of sulphuretted hydrogen per gallon, while the water from the Richwood well contained over eight times as much of this gas, which was one of its most valuable properties. </p>



<p>In October of 1899, the drilling commenced on the second well on William Biddle’s farm located near the first well west of Richwood. As expected, it too proved to be a &#8220;dry&#8221; hole after drilling 1500 feet and was promptly abandoned. Mr. and Mrs. Biddle entertained the four men on the drilling crew at their home when the drilling was complete. Three of the men were Welsh along with Mrs. Biddle who was of Welsh parentage. The evening was spent in the singing of Welsh songs with Mr. Jones, captain of the drilling crew, acting as pianist. Oysters and other refreshments were served. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=524%2C446&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3850" width="524" height="446" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=1024%2C873&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=300%2C256&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=768%2C655&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=1536%2C1310&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=2048%2C1746&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=700%2C597&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=400%2C341&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/Screen-Shot-2022-08-12-at-12.26.55-PM.png?resize=1300%2C1108&amp;ssl=1 1300w" sizes="(max-width: 524px) 100vw, 524px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>A picture of a picnic gathering at Varuna Park circa 1910.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In December, the Richwood, Oil, Gas and Mineral Company met at the mayor&#8217;s office once more and it was decided to organize a stock company for the development of well number 1 on the Sidle farm and put the mineral water on the market. The company was capitalized in the sum of $10,000 and the stock was sold to the members of the Richwood OGM Co. for $10 each as long as any member of the old company wished to do so. After which, it was offered to the rest of the public. </p>



<p>On December 18, 1899, the Varuna Water Company filed their articles of incorporation to the Ohio Secretary of State and began to develop well no. 1 of the old Richwood Oil, Gas, and Mineral Company. The water was named “Varuna” which is a Sanskrit word meaning “the God of Waters.” On December 28, 1899, the stockholders of Varuna Water Company met at the private office of the Deposit Bank in Richwood. After some time, a committee consisting of J.B. Miller, J.M. Wilkins, and George W. Worden was appointed to draft the by-laws and constitution. After they were met with approval, the following list of officers were elected: J.L. Horn, president; J.M. Wilkins, vice president; W.H. Wagers, secretary; and Bent Cahill, treasurer.</p>



<p>The Varuna Water Company contracted with a Baltimore firm for a bottling machine which was placed in the building constructed on the land purchased from C.D. Sidle. The Richwood Gazette published the following story: On February 12, 1900, the president of the Varuna Water Company, J.L. Horn, had opened an airtight lid to one of the big tanks filled with the water. Upon doing so, sulphonated hydrogen gas was so strong that it completely overcame him, and he stepped back from the tank and gently laid down on the floor. As he dropped, his hat fell to the first story of the building where his men were working and went upstairs to see what was wrong. They were surprised to see Mr. Horn lying on the floor sleeping as sweetly as a baby. They attempted to awake him, but it was about five minutes before they could do so. When he finally came to, he said he felt as though he had been chloroformed and that he believed he would have slept longer had he been left alone.<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">1</sup></p>



<p>Varuna water began to sell at the stores of J.L. Horn and Isaac Miller in Richwood. The bottles were sold for 25 cents per gallon. Anyone with stomach, liver, or kidney pain was suggested to try the water. An advertisement in the Richwood Gazette suggested that “If you have that tired feeling and don’t enjoy your food, try Varuna mineral water. It will sharpen up your appetite and make a new man of you.”<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">2</sup></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://www.newspapers.com/clip/83740710/varuna-mineral-water/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://rnulibraryblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/09/varuna-mineral-water-5-apr-1900.jpg?w=725&#038;resize=725%2C1023" alt="" class="wp-image-3413" width="725" height="1023" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption><em>A large advertisement which appeared in the Richwood Gazette on Apr. 5, 1900, featuring testimonials and a chemical analysis of the water.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>On April 17, 1900, the Varuna Water Company made a big shipment of mineral water to their agent, J.W. Thew, at Marion. It was later said that J.B. Miller made arrangements to sell the water in Columbus.</p>



<p>The Richwood Gazette, in their paper on April 19, 1900, claimed that Austin Rose, of west Ottawa St., was surprised to find a full-grown opossum sunning himself on his front porch. Mr. Rose captured it alive and expected to keep it until next summer and then turn it over to the Varuna Water Company for their zoological garden. This was the only mention of such a garden which may or may not have existed.</p>



<p>In June of 1900, the Varuna Water Company began carbonating the water to make it more pleasant and less “nauseating as it was in its natural state.” The carbonating claimed to not destroy its rare medical properties but instead “keeps it pure and makes it sparkle like champagne.”<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">3</sup></p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1915-Verona-Park-Picnic.jpg?resize=589%2C392&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3845" width="589" height="392" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1915-Verona-Park-Picnic.jpg?w=900&amp;ssl=1 900w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1915-Verona-Park-Picnic.jpg?resize=300%2C200&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1915-Verona-Park-Picnic.jpg?resize=768%2C512&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1915-Verona-Park-Picnic.jpg?resize=700%2C467&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/08/1915-Verona-Park-Picnic.jpg?resize=400%2C267&amp;ssl=1 400w" sizes="(max-width: 589px) 100vw, 589px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>An unknown family enjoying a picnic at Varuna Park circa 1910.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>In September 1900, J.L. Horn sold the company over to Isaac Miller. Mr. Miller began extensive improvements, one of which was the creation of a modern bath house. Varuna Park, including the bath house, opened as a pleasure resort at the end of May 1901. The bath house included eight bath rooms, with male and female attendants. Wooden tubs were used for those desiring baths in Varuna well no. 1 since it was claimed that no other material should be used on account of the properties of the water. In the rooms used by well no. 2, porcelain tubs were used. The park itself was fitted with seats, swings and merry-go-rounds. Refreshments were also served on the grounds. It was reported that over 800 people visited the park on its opening day on May 19, 1901.</p>



<p>In June, Mr. Miller began making arrangements to give band concerts at the park every Sunday afternoon during the summer months beginning on June 29 when Prof. Arens, of LaRue, assisted by the LaRue Cornet Band, opened the season. The public was invited to enjoy the “cool and sparkling mineral water to their hearts’ content.”<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">4</sup> No admission to the park was charged.</p>



<p>A new 40-horsepower boiler was purchased for the water plant in July after the old boiler let loose one Sunday morning and blew out one of the heads. Nobody was in the engine room at the time and Mr. Miller was glad that no one was around when the boiler gave out.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><a href="https://ohiomemory.org/digital/collection/p16007coll111/id/10127"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/varuna-park.jpg?resize=542%2C340&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3425" width="542" height="340" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/varuna-park.jpg?resize=1024%2C643&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/varuna-park.jpg?resize=300%2C188&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/varuna-park.jpg?resize=768%2C482&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/varuna-park.jpg?resize=700%2C439&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/varuna-park.jpg?resize=400%2C251&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/varuna-park.jpg?resize=1300%2C816&amp;ssl=1 1300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/varuna-park.jpg?w=1380&amp;ssl=1 1380w" sizes="(max-width: 542px) 100vw, 542px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption><em>A photograph of Varuna Park, appearing on a postcard.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Varuna Park opened for the season on Saturday, June 7, 1902, in the form of a gala day. At 10 o’clock a.m. a grand parade took place in which 100 men on horseback, representing different nationalities, escorted by two brass bands, traversed along the streets of town, and arrived at the park by 11 o’clock. Professional Perry, the high wire wonder, who was famous for juggling, dancing, and riding a bicycle across an ordinary steel wire in midair, was present. Charles G. Parker and “Stump,” his educated dog, was also on the grounds. “Stump” climbed a 50-foot ladder and jumped to a net below. This was purported to have been the highest jump ever made by a trained dog at the time. The two brass bands continued to provide music throughout the day. At 3 o’clock, the attractions at the park were moved to Franklin Street in Richwood where programs were rendered during the evening. All jugs and bottles brought by guests were filled with Varuna water, free of charge. Arrangements were made where anyone could secure excursion rates from any point on the Erie railroad.</p>



<p>In November of 1903, Isaac Miller was forced to declare bankruptcy. His liabilities were about $24,000 with assets of about $10,000. He came to Richwood in 1880 and actively engaged in many businesses. He conducted a successful business and owned considerable real estate up until about three years before the bankruptcy, about the time he purchased Varuna Park and made an effort to improve the park and put Varuna water on the market. The sales of the plant since then were not what they should’ve been and the expenses were very heavy, thereby involving him to such an extent that he was forced to take out money from his other businesses just to keep Varuna Park going. The stock of merchandise formally owned by Mr. Miller was sold in a bankruptcy sale on December 29, 1903. His seventy-two shares of stock in the Varuna Water Co. were sold to Miller&#8217;s nephew from Cleveland.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><a href="https://www.newspapers.com/clip/85093677/richwood-fertilizer-co/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://rnulibraryblog.files.wordpress.com/2021/09/richwood-fertilizer-.jpg?w=900&#038;resize=296%2C336" alt="" class="wp-image-3418" width="296" height="336" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption><em>Advertisement of the Richwood Fertilizer Co. appearing in the Richwood Gazette in 1917.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The land known as Varuna Park continued to be owned by Isaac Miller. On December 23, 1909, Mr. Miller sold ten acres off the south half of Varuna Park to H.H. Beaner who owned the Sidle farm adjoining the park grounds. On May 25, 1916, Mr. Miller sold the Varuna Park to D.C. and James Cushman of Richwood and Max Meyer of Columbus. They installed a fertilizer plant there named the Richwood Fertilizer Company. D.C. Cushman was manager of the establishment and had full charge of the business. A lawsuit was later brought to the company by a Dr. Bown. It was postponed indefinitely on account of the owners agreeing to cease operations of the plant by April 1, 1918. The suit was brought on to prevent the draining of wastewater from the plant into Fulton Creek and to stop the offensive odors.</p>



<p>Varuna Park had continued to be used as a gathering place for the citizens of Richwood. Many picnics and public sales were still being held on the grounds. The Park was used until at least the 1930s. After that time, all mention of Varuna Park ceased, and both the park and the mineral water had faded into obscurity.</p>
<h3 class="modern-footnotes-list-heading ">References</h3><div>1&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, Feb. 22, 1900.</div><div>2&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, March 1, 1900.</div><div>3&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, June 7, 1900.</div><div>4&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, June 27, 1901.</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/varuna-park/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3424</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Richwood Home Coming Week</title>
		<link>/richwood-home-coming-week/</link>
					<comments>/richwood-home-coming-week/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dustin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 27 May 2022 17:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richwood's Past]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[home coming week]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[richwood home coming week]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3729</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;On the 8th day of August, 1832, Thomas G. Plummer, a special deputy surveyor under the direction of Levi Phelps, surveyor of Union county, made the survey of the town site of Richwood, which as that time was in the midst of a dense wilderness. What date could be more appropriate for a Richwood Home...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>&#8220;On the 8th day of August, 1832, Thomas G. Plummer, a special deputy surveyor under the direction of Levi Phelps, surveyor of Union county, made the survey of the town site of Richwood, which as that time was in the midst of a dense wilderness. What date could be more appropriate for a Richwood Home Coming than the first week in August 1910, the seventy-eighth anniversary of our town?&#8221;</p>



<p>This article came from the Richwood Gazette on July 21, 1910. The thought was that the five hundred or so families, who at some point during those 78 years had changed their address, would perhaps wish to visit their old associates and acquaintances in and around Richwood. Flags and banners were strung everywhere in town to welcome visitors. During the week, there were various displays including one in the Mayor&#8217;s office which held many curiosities of pioneer days such as photographs of the early settlers of Richwood, scenes about Richwood in pioneer days, and many other things. The fair was also in session during Home Coming week which included a balloon race and parachute drop, a concert of the Fourth Regiment Military Band, and of course 4 horse races on the &#8220;best half-mile track in the state.&#8221;</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?resize=502%2C368&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3731" width="502" height="368" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?resize=1024%2C750&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?resize=300%2C220&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?resize=768%2C563&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?resize=1536%2C1126&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?resize=700%2C513&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?resize=400%2C293&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?resize=1300%2C953&amp;ssl=1 1300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/wire-walker.jpg?w=1740&amp;ssl=1 1740w" sizes="(max-width: 502px) 100vw, 502px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>While this image was believed to have been taken during Richwood&#8217;s 1876 Centennial Celebration, it is a good example of a high wire performance that was also performed above Franklin Street.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The Richwood Gazette reported that over 600 people came to Richwood during the Home Coming Week. One of the biggest attractions that occurred was a high wire performance by James E. Hardy. He gave a show each day and was greeted by a large crowd each time he attempted his miraculous feats in the air. Tuesday morning, August 2, 1910, at promptly 6:30 before many citizens of Richwood were up ad about, all the whistles were blown, accompanied by the ringing of the church bells and firing of anvils, for ten minutes, formally opening Home Coming week. </p>



<p>The entertainment on Wednesday included a baseball game between the Home Comers and the New Comers, the outcome being 9 to 8 with the old &#8220;has beens&#8221; defeating the younger fellows by one point. This day also included a trip to the Richwood fair and the reunion of the old comrades of Company G, 14th regiment O.N.G. and the old 14th regiment band.</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><a href="https://ohiomemory.org/digital/collection/p16007coll111/id/10199"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=303%2C451&#038;ssl=1" alt="Home Coming week program book" class="wp-image-3733" width="303" height="451" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=688%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 688w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=201%2C300&amp;ssl=1 201w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=768%2C1144&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=1032%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 1032w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=1375%2C2048&amp;ssl=1 1375w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=700%2C1042&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=269%2C400&amp;ssl=1 269w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=470%2C700&amp;ssl=1 470w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home_coming_program_001.jpg?resize=873%2C1300&amp;ssl=1 873w" sizes="(max-width: 303px) 100vw, 303px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption><em>The cover of the official Home Coming week Program Book. Click the image to read through the book.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>Thursday morning witnessed a reunion of the old students and high school alumni at the school building. Reportedly quite a large number of former teachers and students were present.</p>



<p>The  program committee had prepared quite a surprise for everybody in the shape of a picture show for Thursday evening. Photographs of many of the older residents of the town, a few of whom were still living, had been obtained and slides were made from them. The pictures were shown on a screen on the building that was occupied by the Farmers Deposit Bank. The street opposite was jammed with people pushing and scrambling to get as close as possible. Proceeding the show was a sextette composed of J.A. Phillips, S.A. McNeil, Don Van Winkle, C.G. Johnson, Dr. Brown and Fred Rapp, sang the following official song of the Home Comers:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-verse">My Old Richwood Home
<em>Tune, "We'll Stand by the Colors" by J.A. Phillips.</em>
[ALL JOIN IN THE CHORUS]

Where a village stands in splendor
In the grand old Buckeye state,
There the welcomes, warm and tender,
For my wandering footsteps wait.
'Tis the place where hills in glory
Sparkle 'neath the morning's beams.
'Tis the land of song and story,
And the palace of my dreams.

<em>Chorus
Home, sweet home, my dear old Richwood home.
Back where the roses and the wild clematis bloom,
Home, sweet home, I'm going home once more,
Back where the voices of my loved ones bid me come.</em>

I can hear the robins singing
As they sang in days before,
'Mid the morning glories clinging
To the trellis by the door.
I can hear light footsteps falling
When the evening breezes blow,
I can hear loved voices calling
From the days of long ago.

How we linger and we listen
When the dear old song is heard.
How the eyes will dim and glisten
As we harken to each word,
And with happy visions thronging
How we join the sweet refrain,
Till our hearts are filled with longing
For the dear old home again.</pre>



<p>The Richwood Gazette includes a list of names of those whose pictures were shown during the show. A few names include: Dr. John P Brookins, Grandma Brookins, Andrew McNeil, Jacob C. Sidle, Judge Hastings, Uncle Peter Finch, Orrin Beem, Dr. E.Y. King, and Mr. and Mrs. William H. Conkright. </p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=695%2C444&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3736" width="695" height="444" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=1024%2C655&amp;ssl=1 1024w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=300%2C192&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=768%2C491&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=1536%2C982&amp;ssl=1 1536w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=2048%2C1309&amp;ssl=1 2048w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=700%2C448&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=400%2C256&amp;ssl=1 400w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2022/05/Home-Coming-Week-Train.jpg?resize=1300%2C831&amp;ssl=1 1300w" sizes="(max-width: 695px) 100vw, 695px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>A drawn rendering of visitors coming to Richwood Home Coming week on the Columbus, Magnetic Springs and Northern electric line. Appeared in the Richwood Gazette in 1910.</em></figcaption></figure></div>


<p>The grand mardi gras festival on Friday evening concluded the week&#8217;s program and was joined in by both young and old, and dozens of amusing costumes were present. C.J. Fifer, manager of the C.M.S. &amp; N. railway, had the company&#8217;s work car furnished with seats and decorated in flashy colors. Along each side of the car was stretched a large banner bearing the words, &#8220;C.M.S. &amp; N. Summer Car,&#8221; and needless to say the car was packed with jolly masqueraders and amusing costumes with each trip it made through town. The following prizes were given for the best costumes: </p>



<p>Best Uncle Sam, box cigars given by Bruce Street Grocery- won by C.J. Fifer. Hazel Osborn was the best masked lady, and received a pair of kid gloves from the Robinson &amp; Wilkins Co. For the best masked gent the Peet Hardware Co. offered a pocket knife; the judges awarded this prize to Harry E. Peet of the above named firm. Miss Helen McAllister received the china salad dish given by J.W. Kyle &amp; Son for the best Spanish dancing girl. The Roman chair offered by F.L. Winter for the best Indian costume was won by J.G. Smith. George W. Worden was awarded the necktie given by A.I. Glick for the best comic gent. The $2 worth of bathroom essentials offered by M.C. Wolgamot for the best Indian maiden was awarded to Miss Ruby LaDow.</p>



<p>All in all, it seemed as though this Home Coming was a screaming success and surpassed the expectation of even the most optimistic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/richwood-home-coming-week/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3729</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
