<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>alcohol Archives - Dustin K. Lowe</title>
	<atom:link href="/tag/alcohol/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/tag/alcohol/</link>
	<description>Books by Author Dustin K. Lowe</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 18:40:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	

<image>
	<url>https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2019/07/cropped-DL-logo-bg-x144.png?fit=32%2C32&#038;ssl=1</url>
	<title>alcohol Archives - Dustin K. Lowe</title>
	<link>/tag/alcohol/</link>
	<width>32</width>
	<height>32</height>
</image> 
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">160639128</site>	<item>
		<title>Prohibition in Richwood &#8211; Part Two</title>
		<link>/prohibition-in-richwood-part-two/</link>
					<comments>/prohibition-in-richwood-part-two/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dustin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 15 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richwood's Past]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prohibition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Richwood Gazette&#8217;s problems with Prohibition continued with an article on July 14, 1910, in which they accuse the Anti-Saloon League of not wanting to rid Columbus of their saloons. &#8220;If the Anti-Saloon League is so anxious to rid Ohio of the liquor traffic why not begin operations right at home? Directly under the noses...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Richwood Gazette&#8217;s problems with Prohibition continued with an article on July 14, 1910, in which they accuse the Anti-Saloon League of not wanting to rid Columbus of their saloons. &#8220;If the Anti-Saloon League is so anxious to rid Ohio of the liquor traffic why not begin operations right at home? Directly under the noses of the officers of the League in Columbus, are about three hundred saloons. Why not clean them out first? They know full well these saloons are the source of supply for numerous &#8216;dry&#8217; counties in central Ohio and that they attract thousands of people to Columbus every week. Is it possible the League wants to see Columbus &#8216;wet&#8217; and surrounding towns &#8216;dry&#8217; in order to help Columbus financially? It looks very much as if this was the case.&#8221;<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">1</sup></p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-full is-resized"><a href="https://www.newspapers.com/clip/85749595/humorous-snippet-during-prohibition/"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Humorous-Snippet-Dur.jpg?resize=392%2C98&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3510" width="392" height="98" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Humorous-Snippet-Dur.jpg?w=705&amp;ssl=1 705w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Humorous-Snippet-Dur.jpg?resize=300%2C75&amp;ssl=1 300w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Humorous-Snippet-Dur.jpg?resize=700%2C176&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Humorous-Snippet-Dur.jpg?resize=400%2C100&amp;ssl=1 400w" sizes="(max-width: 392px) 100vw, 392px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption><em>Humorous snippet from the Richwood Gazzette, 1908.</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Things further worsened for Richwood when, in December of 1911, the village council was forced to borrow $300 to pay the salaries of village officials. Up until the past three years, Richwood had always had from $3,000 to $5,000 on deposit in the local banks. After the county voted dry in 1908, however, the village was cut short $1,500 a year or a total of $4,500 for the three years, which was the cause of the deficiency in the treasury. Richwood was now in the financial predicament that many, three years ago, foreseen the village would reach. Richwood was not alone in this situation either. Both Milford Center and Marysville had been cut short from $1,500 to $5,000 per annum by the county voting dry.</p>



<p>The Rose law was later modified in 1910, referred to as the Beal law, to allow individual towns and municipalities such as Richwood or Marysville to vote on whether they wanted to remain dry with the county or choose to go wet. The towns of Marion and Prospect did just that. The citizens of Prospect voted under the Beal law and voted wet by a majority of 19 votes. The total votes cast was 304 with 142 voting dry while 161 voted wet. The remaining one vote was illegal. At the county level, Marion County voted dry by a majority of 37 in 1911. Soon afterward, Marion decided to continue their saloon business in the town. Prospect, being between the wet towns of Columbus and Marion and not wanting to lose out on revenue, decided to also continue selling alcohol. They would later vote dry on April 3, 1919 with the resulting closure of the saloon operated by Schelgel and Speyer. </p>



<p>By 1914, a total of 45 counties were considered dry in the state of Ohio. An election was held in Ohio on November 3, 1914. Four different amendments were on the ballot. Amendment 1 provided home rule on alcohol which allowed the citizens of local municipalities and townships the right to decide, without state intervention, if they wanted to sell alcohol or not. Amendment 2 provided limitation on tax rate and property classification. Amendment 3 provided voting rights for women. Amendment 4 would enact a prohibition on the sale of alcohol as beverages in the state of Ohio.<a href="https://ballotpedia.org/Ohio_Home_Rule_on_Alcohol,_Amendment_1_(1914)"> Amendment 1</a> was the only one on the ballot that passed. Below is an advertisement in the Richwood Gazette paid for by the Anti-Saloon League who supported prohibition:</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele-650x1024.jpg?resize=650%2C1024&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3514" width="-149" height="-235" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=650%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 650w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=191%2C300&amp;ssl=1 191w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=768%2C1209&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=976%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 976w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=1301%2C2048&amp;ssl=1 1301w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=700%2C1102&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=254%2C400&amp;ssl=1 254w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=445%2C700&amp;ssl=1 445w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/November-3-1914-Ele.jpg?resize=826%2C1300&amp;ssl=1 826w" sizes="(max-width: 650px) 100vw, 650px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption><em>An advertisement in the Richwood Gazette following the election on November 3, 1914. This ad urged voters to vote Yes on prohibition and No on the home rule amendment. </em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>In terms of results for political office, Warren G. Harding was elected to the United States Senate with Frank B. Willis being elected as Ohio Governor. The state legislature was comprised of mostly Republicans. The home rule amendment was later taken to the Ohio Supreme Court after a case was brought in by Franklin County Common Pleas Court by Charles S. Hockett, a piano dealer from Bellefontaine. He alleged that this amendment violated the general welfare provision of the federal constitution and that an attempt was being made to divest the people of certain rights of which they, themselves, could not put aside. The case was pressed for counsel by the Anti-Saloon League. It was appealed and the Supreme Court held that the amendment was in fact valid. </p>



<p>The state liquor licensing board announced in 1915 that the thirty-one counties which will get county license boards under the home rule amendment will have a total of 493 saloons (versus 823 saloons in those counties in 1908, before the votes to dry). Union county had a total of 9 saloons open. The Anti-Saloon League continued their fight to repeal the home rule amendment and aimed to pass a state-wide prohibition of alcohol. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-full is-resized"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/across-from-dennys-drive-through-speyers-cafe.jpg?resize=363%2C529&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3537" width="363" height="529" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/across-from-dennys-drive-through-speyers-cafe.jpg?w=450&amp;ssl=1 450w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/across-from-dennys-drive-through-speyers-cafe.jpg?resize=206%2C300&amp;ssl=1 206w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/across-from-dennys-drive-through-speyers-cafe.jpg?resize=274%2C400&amp;ssl=1 274w" sizes="(max-width: 363px) 100vw, 363px" data-recalc-dims="1" /><figcaption>P.J. <em>Speyer&#8217;s Cafe located on North Franklin Street in Richwood, circa 1900. The cafe was one of two other establishments in Richwood that were forced to stop selling alcohol when the Rose law was enacted in Union county in 1908.</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>Residents in Claibourne Township, outside of Richwood, quietly circulated a petition to hold a vote on June 23, 1917 to decide if the township should permit saloons to start selling alcohol again. A similar petition and subsequent vote was presented to the citizens of Richwood in January of 1915 and was not passed. In fact, the election was taken to the Supreme Court of Ohio. The drys won by a majority of one vote since a couple votes on both sides of the issue were marked as invalid. The courts decided in favor of the drys and Richwood remained as such. Those who supported the prohibition of alcohol were fearful of saloons being operated outside the city limits which is exactly what a few citizens of Claibourne Township tried to do. The petition filed contained names in excess of the number required by law. Under the home rule amendment, only those who resided in Claibourne Township and outside the city limits of Richwood were permitted to vote on the resolution. Dry voters outnumbered the wets ten to one and the resolution was not passed.</p>



<p>As the first World War raged, the Unites States Congress passed the temporary Wartime Prohibition Act, which banned the sale of alcoholic beverages having an alcohol content of greater than 1.28%. This act, which had been intended to save grain for the war effort, was passed after the armistice ending World War I was signed on November 11, 1918. The Wartime Prohibition Act took effect June 30, 1919, with July 1, 1919 becoming known as the &#8220;Thirsty First.&#8221; The U.S. Senate proposed the Eighteenth Amendment on December 18, 1917. On October 28, 1919, Congress passed enabling legislation, known as the Volstead Act, to enforce the Eighteenth Amendment when it went into effect in 1920. Upon being approved by a 36th state (Ohio being one of them) on January 16, 1919, the amendment was ratified as a part of the Constitution. By the terms of the amendment, the country went dry one year later, on January 17, 1920 when the Volstead Act went into effect. A total of 1,520 Federal Prohibition agents were tasked with enforcement.</p>



<p>Doctors were able to prescribe medicinal alcohol for their patients. After just six months of prohibition, over 15,000 doctors and 57,000 pharmacists received licenses to prescribe or sell medicinal alcohol. A majority of U.S. citizens obeyed the law, although some states like Maryland and New York refused prohibition. Enforcement of the amendment lacked a centralized authority. Many churches formed vigilante groups to enforce it along with organizations such as the Ku Klux Klan, although it was poorly organized and seldom had any impact. As the Great Depression hit in 1929, state governments needed the tax revenue that alcohol sales generated. When Franklin Roosevelt was elected in 1932, he strongly urged the repeal of Prohibition. The Eighteenth Amendment was officially repealed on December 5, 1933 with ratification of the Twenty-first Amendment to the U.S. Constitution. The Twenty-first Amendment didn&#8217;t prevent states and municipalities from banning or restricting alcohol thereby allowing local control of alcohol. With the Amendment gone, the country was effectively half wet and half dry.</p>



<p>In November 1933, Richwood held an election to vote on the mayoral race. Included on the ballot was an option to repeal the ban on the sale of liquor in Richwood. 619 total votes were against the repeal with 487 votes for. Richwood continued to remain dry even after local elections in 1937 and in 1941 where the citizens of Richwood once again voted against the sale of liquor in Richwood by a nice majority. The elections in 1945 onward included no mention of the prohibition of liquor. It&#8217;s currently not know when, if ever, Richwood officially voted to once again allow the sale of liquor. Despite this, liquor sales have since continued in Richwood and no enforcement has been made. </p>



<p>With the end of the Prohibition Amendment, one thing became pretty clear. By prohibiting these sales, the state of Ohio as well as the United States economy would see large losses directly and indirectly from alcohol sales. Supporters of the prohibition expected an increase in the sales of other products such as other beverages like juice and soda to replace the money made from alcohol sales, but this could not be further from reality. The Bureau of Internal Revenue estimated that the prohibition caused the shutdown of over 200 distilleries, a thousand breweries, and over 170,000 liquor stores. Organized criminal organizations saw this as an opportunity to make a lot of cash. Enforcement of the ban had to be paid for to fight the war against both alcohol and crime. The amount of money used to enforce prohibition started at 6.3 million in 1921 and rose to 13.4 million in 1930, almost double the original amount.</p>



<p>If you&#8217;d like to learn more about Prohibition, I highly recommend the book <em><a href="https://amzn.to/3DIsFAO" rel="sponsored nofollow">Last Call: The Rise and Fall of Prohibition</a></em> by Daniel Okrent as well as<em> <a href="https://amzn.to/3AGtyIu" rel="sponsored nofollow">Prohibition in Columbus, Ohio</a> </em>by Alexander Tebben for a more local history of the Prohibition Movement. Both books can be checked out at your local library.</p>
<h3 class="modern-footnotes-list-heading ">References</h3><div>1&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, July 14, 1910.</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/prohibition-in-richwood-part-two/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3508</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Prohibition in Richwood &#8211; Part One</title>
		<link>/prohibition-in-richwood-part-one/</link>
					<comments>/prohibition-in-richwood-part-one/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dustin]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2021 14:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Richwood's Past]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[alcohol]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[prohibition]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=3475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Prohibition Movement began following the more moderate Temperance Movement after the American Civil War had ended. The Temperance Movement encouraged people to abstain from selling or drinking alcohol. It wasn&#8217;t about prohibition, that is, passing laws that compelled people to behave in a particular way. Instead, it was a movement grounded in moral persuasion;...]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Prohibition Movement began following the more moderate Temperance Movement after the American Civil War had ended. The Temperance Movement encouraged people to abstain from selling or drinking alcohol. It wasn&#8217;t about prohibition, that is, passing laws that compelled people to behave in a particular way. Instead, it was a movement grounded in moral persuasion; by changing individual behavior by influencing. Temperance supporters believed that freedom meant something very particular. Freedom meant freedom from addictive vices and bad habits and undermines self-discipline, self-improvement, and respectability. Today we tend to see the consumption of alcohol less as a bad habit that oppresses individuals but rather as a consumer choice. It doesn&#8217;t matter what you choose, only that <strong>you</strong> choose. For Temperance Crusaders, however, abstaining from alcohol was a liberating act; it was an act that demonstrated you could govern yourself.</p>



<p>The Temperance Movement resonated with many Ohioans. One possible reason is that Ohioans had experienced intense urbanization, industrialization and emigration. Its cities struggled with urban squalor, economic exploitation and poverty. Migration and emigration to this world was alienating. Most new Ohioans had lived as their ancestors had lived for countless centuries. The modern world of anonymous cities, brutal factories and dense city living was stressful and challenged the stability of family life. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignleft size-large is-resized"><a href="https://www.loc.gov/item/2003656595/"><img decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?resize=337%2C501&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3517" width="337" height="501" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?resize=688%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 688w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?resize=202%2C300&amp;ssl=1 202w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?resize=768%2C1143&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?resize=700%2C1042&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?resize=269%2C400&amp;ssl=1 269w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?resize=470%2C700&amp;ssl=1 470w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?resize=873%2C1300&amp;ssl=1 873w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/12/Womans-Holy-War.jpg?w=1032&amp;ssl=1 1032w" sizes="(max-width: 337px) 100vw, 337px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption><em>The Temperance Movement was referred to as the &#8220;Woman&#8217;s Holy War.&#8221; Drawing was done by Currier &amp; Ives.</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>The aftereffects of the American Civil War also played a part. After the war, there was a noticeable increase in alcohol consumption. In the small town of Washington Courthouse, for example, the number of saloon keepers expanded from zero in 1860 to eight in 1870 all for about 2,000 residents. Clearly, the aftershocks of war added to the stress of a state undergoing rapid transformation. Alcohol seemed to offer a salve against social change and post-traumatic stress. </p>



<p>Over the course of 1873 to 1874, there were Temperance Crusades in 31 states and territories involving some 54 thousand women; 60% of those women protested in Ohio. They marched down Main streets, they drafted petitions, they got pledges from people to stop drinking, they picketed saloons by singing hymns at the door as men passed in and out. Often, they were harassed, jostled by men, spat upon, drenched in old beer and dirty water. In Ohio alone, there were 300 Crusades in 200 different places. The women of Washington courthouse, for example, had great success as they managed to persuade the owners of all of the bars to shut down.</p>



<p>The Temperance Movement was later eclipsed by the Prohibition Movement which compelled people to stop drinking. That movement was also set in Ohio and it was led by the Anti-Saloon League which was founded in Oberlin, Ohio in 1893 and relocated to Westerville in 1909. This movement, unlike the Temperance Movement, was led mainly by men. They focused their efforts on the complete abolition of the sale of alcohol through outlets such as saloons. The organization was effective and was able to build off of the Temperance Movement. But, more than any other organization, they helped persuade America to amend the constitution, ratifying the 18th amendment in 1919 to outlaw the manufacture and distribution of alcohol. An important fact to note here is that it wasn&#8217;t illegal to drink alcohol, just creating and selling it.</p>



<p>By 1908, there were a total of fifteen various saloons in Union county; eight in Marysville, three in Richwood, three at Milford Center and one in Magnetic Springs. A petition containing the signatures of 3412 voters was filed on September 9th, 1908 with the Common Pleas Judge in Marysville. The petition called for a special election on October 5th under the Rose Bill. The Rose Bill, also called the Rose Law, allowed individual communities to put Prohibition issues on their local ballots. If a majority of residents voted in favor of the issue, then saloons could not operate in the community. Many Ohio towns and cities took advantage of the Rose Law to ban the sale of alcohol in their communities. The Union County Board of Elections were then ordered to have ballots printed for a special election.</p>



<p>The Richwood Gazette posted an article in the paper in September titled, &#8220;Attention Farmers and Land Owners: Your vote is Important. Carefully examine the following figures from the State Auditor&#8217;s Reports for 1907 then decide for yourself how you honestly think you should cast your ballot.&#8221; The article lists the following facts and figures taken from the Ohio Auditor of State&#8217;s Report of 1907:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">1- By levying a state tax of 1.345 mills on all tangible property, the state of Ohio derived......$3,012,115.05
2- The state received from the liquor tax.........................................................$2,749,750.99
3- The state received from all other sources of revenue...........................................$780,732.70
Total revenue of the state in 1907................................................................$6,542,598.74</pre>



<p>The Gazette then pointed out that if the saloons in Ohio were voted out of existence, at least $2,749,750.99 in revenue of the state would be destroyed. This revenue is 91.5 per cent of the total amount ($3,012,115.05) the state raised by direct taxation by a state levy of 1,345 mills. &#8220;This revenue must be made from some other source, and that source will be by direct taxation on your farm, your real estate, and your house, for this class of property is sure to bear the brunt of the inevitable increased taxation.&#8221; The liquor tax paid for 42% of the running expenses of the state. The Gazette warned that the state tax rate would double to compensate for the loss of revenue. They later state, &#8220;Do not be led astray by fanatical and emotional appeals from the non-taxpaying Anti-Saloon League and its salaried itinerant agitators.&#8221;<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">1</sup></p>



<p>The Richwood Gazette publishes an article a week later exposing the &#8220;false statements&#8221; made by the Anti-Saloon League. The paper claims that the organization lies about a reduction in taxes that follows wherever the income from the liquor tax is wiped out. &#8220;This on its very face sound very paradoxical.&#8221; They later point out that, &#8220;It stands to reason that when you destroy one source of income, the difference must be made up somewhere else.&#8221;<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">2</sup> The organization likes to point to Washington Courthouse as a good example of this. When called upon to explain this strange condition, they point out that the town didn&#8217;t need as many policeman which made up the loss of the liquor tax. The Gazette delves into this by providing the expenses paid to police in the town:</p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted">                                1904        1905        1906        1907
Paid for police duty..........$2887.00    $3050.00    $1506.00    $1854.00
Received from liquor tax......$1902.05    $1806.07    $223.62     ________
</pre>



<p>It should be added that Washington Courthouse had four policemen while the town was &#8220;wet,&#8221; and that when the revenue from the liquor tax was cut off, expenses had to be curtailed so that in May, 1906, and for the balance of that year there was only one regular policeman on the pay roll of the town. More policeman were needed as shown by the increase in 1907&#8217;s numbers. However, the biggest reduction in funding was for public services such as street repairs, street cleaning, sewage, public lighting, ect. In 1905, the public services fund in the town was 7.75 mills. In 1908, that had been reduced to 6 mills. As used in property tax, 1 mill is equal to $1 in property tax levied per $1,000 of a property&#8217;s assessed value. It can therefore be seen that a loss in the liquor tax actually did require the town to make up the difference in other ways despite not raising the taxes on residents. </p>



<p>Despite the Gazette&#8217;s constant insistence otherwise, Union county had overwhelmingly voted &#8220;dry.&#8221; By a decisive majority of 1799, the voters of Union county, regardless of politics, had decided that they disproved of the continuation of saloons. Reportedly, many men who were addicted to alcohol also voted dry to try to kick the habit. The total number of votes cast in the county was 5721, the largest voting number in the history of the county at the time. Of this number, the drys voted 3738 and the wets 1935. The drys won every municipality and township in the county except for Darby township which gave wets the majority by a total of 23 votes. Below is the complete tally of votes in all townships in Union county:</p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="aligncenter size-large is-resized"><a href="https://www.newspapers.com/clip/85747820/results-of-the-1908-prohibition-vote-in/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?resize=264%2C579&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3496" width="264" height="579" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?resize=467%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 467w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?resize=137%2C300&amp;ssl=1 137w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?resize=701%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 701w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?resize=700%2C1533&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?resize=183%2C400&amp;ssl=1 183w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?resize=320%2C700&amp;ssl=1 320w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?resize=593%2C1300&amp;ssl=1 593w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Results-of-the-1908-.jpg?w=703&amp;ssl=1 703w" sizes="(max-width: 264px) 100vw, 264px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption><em>Results of the special election which resulted in the closing of saloons that served alcohol in Union county in 1908. </em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>As a result of the election, all fifteen saloons in Union county were forced to close. The Rose local option law went into effect on November 4th, 1908 at 9:30 pm. Saturday evening on October 31, P.J. Speyer closed the doors to his saloon for good, having sold all his stock, and expressed interest in converting his building to a restaurant and pool hall. The two other bars in Richwood, owned by Carl Allgower and Ira Donahoe, were closed on November 4th at the same time that the law went into effect.</p>



<p>The town of Kenton had also voted dry around the same year. According to a discovery reported by a visitor from Bellefontaine, they started selling whiskey in oranges. &#8220;&#8216;Give me two oranges,&#8217; said the Bellefontaine visitor, as he threw down a silver dollar. They were carefully handed out accompanied by a wink from the dealer. The Bellefontaine man examined them before asking for change, and found inside of each orange a tin circular flask containing whisky. The purchaser of the oranges did not ask for change.&#8221;<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">3</sup></p>



<p>Despite the prohibition of alcohol taking effect, many people were still able to get their fix one way or another. Some stores had underground bars which served alcohol illegally and others attempted to make alcohol themselves which caused many people to get sick. Bootleg alcohol was often of lesser quality and sometimes even dangerous. On average, 1,000 Americans died every year during Prohibition from the effects of drinking tainted liquor. </p>



<div class="wp-block-image"><figure class="alignright size-large is-resized"><a href="https://www.newspapers.com/clip/85905951/alcohol-ad/"><img loading="lazy" decoding="async" src="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=338%2C649&#038;ssl=1" alt="" class="wp-image-3504" width="338" height="649" srcset="https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=533%2C1024&amp;ssl=1 533w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=156%2C300&amp;ssl=1 156w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=768%2C1477&amp;ssl=1 768w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=799%2C1536&amp;ssl=1 799w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=1065%2C2048&amp;ssl=1 1065w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=700%2C1346&amp;ssl=1 700w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=208%2C400&amp;ssl=1 208w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=364%2C700&amp;ssl=1 364w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?resize=676%2C1300&amp;ssl=1 676w, https://i0.wp.com/www.dustinlowe.com/wp-content/uploads/2021/09/Alcohol-Ad.jpg?w=1361&amp;ssl=1 1361w" sizes="(max-width: 338px) 100vw, 338px" data-recalc-dims="1" /></a><figcaption><em>A whiskey advertisement appearing in the Richwood Gazette in 1913, five years after Union county had voted dry. Whiskey was often used for &#8220;medicinal&#8221; purposes.</em></figcaption></figure></div>



<p>A man by the name of Ogan was voted as Mayor of Richwood on the first day of the year in 1910 and promised many reforms. The first thing he did was rearrange the Mayor&#8217;s office and made a much needed cleaning of the entire premises. He then called all members of the new council and talked over many things which might be improved upon in the town. One of the things talked about at this conference was the enforcement of the curfew ordinance which was passed by the council a few years prior. It was enforced for a time and was the means of keeping many children off the streets during the night unless accompanied by a parent or guardian. It was decided to enforce this curfew again and on the first night of the new year, Marshal Sloop cleared the streets of the usual gang of children who had been in the habit of loitering in the streets late at night.</p>



<p>The &#8220;bootlegger&#8221; problem also came up for discussion and it was of the councils opinion that the &#8220;bootlegger&#8221; and &#8220;common drunks&#8221; who make it a point to loiter around the corners and alleys of Richwood be made to obey to ordinances of the town and laws of Ohio. Since Richwood and Union county voted the town &#8220;dry&#8221; in 1908, and thereby imposed an extra tax of $1500 per annum upon the taxpayers of Richwood, it was of the opinion that as long as the town remains &#8220;dry&#8221; in name, it should also be &#8220;dry&#8221; in reality.</p>



<p>On April 9, 1910, a twenty-two year old man by the name of Omer DeGood was arrested that morning while on his way to the fairgrounds with a basket filled with whiskey and beer. He was locked up in the village prison and a search and seizure warrant sworn out by Marshal Sloop who, together with Deputy Marshal Aller, went to the home of the parents of Mr. DeGood who resided on North Franklin street. They succeeded in finding many empty bottles of whiskey and jugs. The officers hauled the goods off to the Mayor&#8217;s office in grocery carts.</p>



<p>That evening, DeGood was given a preliminary hearing before Mayor Ogan and plead not guilty to bootlegging and was placed under $300 bond. Failing to come up with the required bond, he was again placed in the village prison to wait until Tuesday morning for a hearing. When he appeared before the hearing that morning, he again plead not guilty. In the meantime, Marshal Sloop and others had done what they could to provide direct evidence where it could be proven that Mr. DeGood violated the Rose Law. Although this was impossible to prove, the next best thing for the officers to do was to banish the young man from the town. There were many complaints before this incident against his conduct. He agreed to this arrangement and signed an article stating that he was not to return to Richwood. The Richwood Gazette points out that, &#8220;The Rose law is a failure in many respects and has not accomplished much good in Union county, which was voted dry by a big majority. Since its passage it is said by those in a position to know that there is as much, if not more whisky consumed than before the saloons were voted out. They say it has changed many moderate beer drinkers to consumers of whiskey and other stimulants detrimental to the general health.&#8221;<sup class="modern-footnotes-footnote modern-footnotes-footnote--hover-on-desktop ">4</sup></p>
<h3 class="modern-footnotes-list-heading ">References</h3><div>1&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, September 17, 1908.</div><div>2&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, September 24, 1908.</div><div>3&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, January 28, 1909.</div><div>4&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;Richwood Gazette, April 14, 1910.</div>]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/prohibition-in-richwood-part-one/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">3475</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
